Contact

+97430406039 (Mobile) salim.houari@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/salim-houari (LinkedIn) earn.com (Other)

github.com/shouari (Other)

Top Skills

Management

Negotiation

Business Strategy

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Arabic (Native or Bilingual)

French (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Verified International Academic Qualifications

J.T. O'Donnell on Making Recruiters
Come to You

Online Marketing Foundations Scientific Computing with Python

Salim Houari

Deputy Manager at Software development Company Qatar

Summary

For about a decade, I've been committed to achievement, working hard on creating sustainable performances based on practical decisions.

As engineer, I learned to be efficient, critical and problem solver. I make use of those skills whether in marketing, supply chain or management.

I strongly believe in team synergy and I would not be able to succeed as manager without the support of my team.

Even with more than 10 years experience, I consider myself as fresher, learning everyday and enriching my skills set.

Beside Marketing and business in general, I am a photography enthusiastic and new technology addict especially AI and machine learning.

Experience

Confidential
Deputy Manager
September 2020 - Present (5 months)
Doha, Qatar

Self-employed Marketing and Business Consultant May 2016 - September 2020 (4 years 5 months) Algiers, Algeria

As consultant my role includes (but not limited to):

Self Employed •Study company profile and operations to understand its marketing needs

Evaluate company's competition and its competitors
 Algiers

Page 1 of 6

- •Develop and implement a marketing strategy according to objectives and budget
- •Prepare detailed proposals and marketing plans
- •Advise on branding, positioning, communications and other marketing issues
- Monitor marketing projects and analyze results
- •Review and monitor strategies of the company. On sales, advertising, marketing, and other related fields of business
- Create opportunities for new product/ service by networking
- •Initiate strategies and plans for the company to reduce its losses and instead achieve increased profits

Confidential

Sr. Business consultant July 2019 - July 2020 (1 year 1 month)

Doha, Qatar

Company Specialized in Home automation systems, and reporting to the Business Development General Manager I was handling:

Communicating with clients to understand their needs and explain product value.

Building relationships with clients based on trust and respect.

Present new products and services and enhance existing relationships.

Work with technical staff and other internal colleagues to meet customer needs.

Arrange and participate in internal and external client debriefs.

Prospect for potential new local and international partners and turn this into increased business.

Identify potential partners, and the decision makers within the partner organization.

Research and build relationships with new partners.

Present to and consult with management on business trends with a view to developing new services, products, and distribution channels.

Identify opportunities for new business, services and solutions that will lead to an increase in revenues.

Ssangyong Motor Company Sales & Marketing November 2018 - July 2019 (9 months)

Doha, Qatar

Follow up with prospects portfolio

Reply to all received inquiries through various channels (messenger, phone...)

Coach and direct sales representative

Formulate, direct marketing activities on Social media to promote products & offers

Performance monitoring of sales representatives

Target setting, and performance monitoring of sales representatives

Present sales, revenue and expenses reports and realistic forecasts to the management team

Managing the marketing budget

Stock management & Procurement

Production order preparation

Reporting sales and updated rundown to SYMC

Reporting monthly marketing activities

Develop pricing & Product strategy, balancing firm objectives and customer satisfaction

Design Identify, develop, and evaluate marketing strategy, based on knowledge of established objectives, market characteristics, cost and markup factors.

Design, implement and improve processes to insure lean operations flow

SARL Foton Algerie Marketing & distribution General Manager December 2013 - January 2017 (3 years 2 months) Rouiba

- Managing the marketing budget Develop pricing strategies, balancing firm objectives and customer satisfaction.
- Identify, develop, and evaluate marketing strategy, based on knowledge of establishment objectives, market characteristics, and cost and markup factors.
- Formulate, direct and coordinate marketing activities and policies to promote products and services, working with advertising and promotion managers.
- Direct the hiring, training, and performance evaluations of marketing and sales staff and oversee their daily activities.
- Negotiate contracts with vendors and distributors to manage product distribution, establishing distribution networks and developing distribution strategies.

Concept Investment - Is your business ready? We are an investment and management consultancy

Business Developer

September 2016 - October 2016 (2 months)

Doha, Qatar

An exiting short period project conducted with Concept Qatar on smart building business promotion in Qatar

Alin1 Trading

Co- Founder & Marketing & Operation Manager April 2012 - March 2014 (2 years)

Algiers

- Company business is food and beverage packaging and export, main tasks
- Creating the company and managing all paperwork
- · Establishing business plan
- · Purchase and installation of the packaging line
- Negotiating with suppliers and clients
- · Piloting the sourcing of raw materials and packaging
- Developing the distribution network for the products

Volvo Trucks Sales Manager May 2011 - April 2012 (1 year)

Algeria

- Collaborates with Marketing in establishing and recommending the most realistic sales goals for the company.
- Manages an assigned geographic sales area or product line to maximize sales revenues and meet corporate objectives.
- Establishes and manages effective programs to compensate, coach, appraise and train sales personnel
- Negotiating with fleet customers and government deals

Cevital SPA

Category Manager General Procurement November 2010 - May 2011 (7 months)

- forecasting levels of demand for services and products to meet the business needs and keeping a constant check on stock levels;
- conducting research to ascertain the best products and suppliers in terms of best value, delivery schedules and quality;
- liaising between suppliers, manufacturers, relevant internal departments and customers;
- identifying potential suppliers, visiting existing suppliers, and building and maintaining good relationships with them;

- negotiating and agreeing contracts and monitoring their progress, checking the quality of service provided;
- giving presentations about market analysis and possible growth;
- evaluating bids and making recommendations based on commercial and technical factors;

Toyota Algerie

HINO product planner

August 2009 - November 2010 (1 year 4 months)

Order products from HINO MOTROS LTD

- · Negotiate the price, set the retail sales price
- Insure the right dispatch through the network
- Follow up of Hino business development in Algeria
- Establishment and improvement of procedures within the division

Abdul Latif Jameel

Marketing & Sales support

September 2008 - August 2009 (1 year)

Lebanon

Enrolled in a one year short term mobility program in Beirut lebanoun

Main business of ALJICO is cars distribution in many countries.

Reporting to the Strategic Business Development GM

I was responsible of:

- Following up the implementation of Toyota way in Sales & Marketing among the countries
- Providing guidance regarding Jyukyu (Toyota demand & supply operations) management implementation
- Supporting our distributors in the communication with suppliers (Toyota, Daihatsu, Hino, Subaru) -

Support the strategic business development manager in securing

the business and seeking new businesses

Contribute to the establishment of the company strategy

- Establish and implement the procedure and standards in marketing and sales to suit with global strategy of the group

Toyota Algerie

Product & ordering Planner

August 2006 - September 2008 (2 years 2 months)

TOYOTA ALGERIE is the sister company of ALJICO, it is acting in the distribution of Toyota, Daihatsu, Hino and Subaru cars in Algeria

Reporting to Sales & Marketing GM and Country GM, I was responsible of:

- order products from

Toyota Motors Corp and other principal.

- Negotiate the price, set the retail sales price
- Insure the right dispatch through the network
- Handling the launch and the establishment of Hino business in Algeria
- Coordinating with other departments to Kaizen (improve) procedures.

Main achievement:

- Conduct a successful stock renewal operation
- Implemented a procedure for AC installation
- Set up a procedure for accessories installation
- Establish a business plan for Hino sales & mp; marketing division
- Successful launch of Hino business in Algeria
- Conducted a training for Hino sales men

Education

Ecole Nationale Polytechnique (ENP) - Algeria Engineer, Mechanical Engineering · (1999 - 2006)